EYA ABID

Software Engineer

@ eyaabid60@gmail.com **** +216 58975985 Manouba, Tunisie in https://www.linkedin.com/in/eya-abid-44953021a/ https://github.com/eyaaabid



EXPERIENCE

Web Developer intern(End of Studies internship)

Hexagone SAS

January 2024 - July 2024

▼ Tunisia

• Led the development and implementation of an innovative Content Authoring Manager (CAM) application tailored for the pharmaceutical sector, aimed at streamlining content creation processes, enhancing collaboration, and optimizing distribution strategies.

Figma

React.Js

PHP Symfony

Docker

Mobile Developer intern

Teamwill Consulting

July 2023 - August 2023

- Created a feature-rich mobile app with Flutter to enhance user access to training programs.
- Established a registration system with Strapi and Node.js for easy user signup to training sessions.
- Built a robust Node.js backend to efficiently manage user data, training schedules, and registrations.
- Integrated RESTful APIs to dynamically display training information, keeping users informed about upcoming sessions.

Figma

Flutter

NodeJs

Strapi

Web developer intern

Brainnest

🛗 January 2023 - February 2023

- Enhanced website responsiveness and design consistency with Bootstrap for streamlined development.
- Enhanced website interactivity using JavaScript and jQuery, including dynamic product displays, image sliders, and client-side form validation.
- Secured online transactions and protected customer data by integrating JavaScript-based payment gateways.

Figma

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

PHP

JQuery

UI/UX Designer

Freelancer

July 2023 - Present

♥ Tunis. Tunisia

Figma

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Development of a Platform

Tek-upers

December 2023

▼ Tek-up University, Tunisia

• Development of a platform to connect technology and computer enthusiasts, share ideas, and create meaningful connections.

React.Js

Node.Js

ABOUT ME

As a Software Engineer with a flair for web and mobile development and a passion for UI/UX design, I blend creativity with technology to craft digital experiences that resonate. I'am Extremely motivated to constantly develop my skills and to improve professionally. I am confident in my ability to come up with interesting ideas.

EDUCATION

Computer Science engineering **Tek-up University**

National Entrance Exam to **Engineering School**

₩ Juin 2021

♥ Tunis, Tunisia

Pre-Engineering Student The Faculty of Sciences of Tunis FST

Mathematics Baccalaureate degree **Hannibal High School**

CERTFICATIONS

Oracle Cloud Infrastructure Foundations

₩ July 2023

Oracle University

AWS Academy Graduate - AWS **Academy Cloud Foundations**

Movember 2022

AWS

AWS Machine Learning

August 2022

♀ Udacity

Python data structures

September 2020

♀ University of Michigan

Programming for Everybody (Getting started with Python)

iuly 2020 iii july 2020 ii july 2020 iii ju

♀ University of Michigan

Development of a web application

CRM

May 2023

▼ Tek-up University,Tunisia

• implementation of a tailored CRM system to enhance customer relationships and streamline operations.

 Vue Js
 Node Js
 GraphQL
 Appolo
 TypeScript
 JavaScript

 mongoDB

Development of a web application

EHospital

March 2023

▼ Tek-up University, Tunisia

Developement of an online clinic management system to streamline appointments, patient records, and administrative tasks, improving overall healthcare efficiency.

C-Sharp ASP.Net .Net Core

Development of a mobile application

Coffee Shop

December 2022

♀ Tek-up University, Tunisia

 Development of a cross-platform Android application for a Coffee Shop where clients can place orders and pay them through their phone.

Figma Android Firebase

Development of a mobile application

SOS Home

Movember 2022

▼ Tek-up University, Tunisia

• Development of a cross-platform Flutter application for Home services .

Figma Flutter Firebase

Development of a banking application

Safety Bank

Ctober 2022

▼ Tek-up University,Tunisia

 Development of a Java Desktop application in order to manage a Bank service.

Spring Boot | MySQL

SKILLS

Programming Languages

• HTML CSS PYTHON C
C JAVA JAVASCRIPT DART
TypeScript

Framework

Flutter NodeJs ASP.NET
 Spring Boot Angular Unity Vue.Js
 BOOTSTRAP Express

Database

MySQL SQL Server Oracle
 MongoDB

DevOps

• GIT

Version Control System

• GITHUB GitLab

Project Management

• Agile Scrum Ms Project

Soft Skills

Hard-working Persuasive
 MotivatorLeader Communication
 Team Work

LANGUAGES

Arabic Native

English Onset (B2)

French Full Proficiency

German Elementary Proficiency

SOCIAL ACTIVITIES

Treasurer of iTree Club

Member of Itunes Club

Participant in Tek-up Digital Future

Seminar

OTHER INTERESTS

Sports Music Writing Travel